<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_description">Android drawer icon with material design animation</string>
    <string name="drawer_open">drawer_open</string>
    <string name="drawer_close">drawer_close</string>
    <string name="app_name">Italian Futurism</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="profile_background" />
    <string name="profile_pic" />
    <string name="fillipobio">

        Filippo Tommaso Emilio Marinetti was born on the 22nd of December 1876 in Alexandria Egypt. Marinetti is known best for being one of the
        founding members of The Futurist Movement and as the author of the Futurist Manifesto, which was published in French daily newspaper, Le Figaro
        on the 20th of February 1909.\n \n

        This manifesto proclaimed a new kind of poetry, exalting the love of danger, aggression, speed and war (‘the war’s only hygiene’) and the excitement of
        great crowds, revolutions, industry and technology. Marinetti urged the destruction of museums, libraries and academies. His ideas were extended to
        figurative art in the Manifesto dei pittori futuristi (1910), signed by Giacomo Balla, Umberto Boccioni, Carlo Carrà, Luigi Russolo and Gino Severini.
        In 1910 the manifestos were declaimed in riotous soirées throughout Italy.\n \n

        His Futurist theories developed to cover areas other than literature and the visual arts: for example in 1914 he organized a series of conferences in London launching the manifesto Abbasso il tango e Parsifal condemning two dance styles that he considered decadent and degenerate.
        As well as dance, Marinetti\’s ideas concerned music, drama, film and such applied arts as industrial and graphic design, ceramics, textiles, bookbinding
        and metalwork. He also himself experimented with the plastic arts, for example in the Self-portrait (Dynamic Combination of Objects) (priv. col., see
        Belloli, 1982, p. 86), made of polychrome woods, matchboxes, various brushes and a grey silk handkerchief, hung from the centre of the main ceiling of the
        Doré Gallery in London in 1914.\n \n

        In the late 1920s and 1930s Marinetti supported the phase of Futurist painting known as Aeropittura. He himself practised and theorized about
        \‘aeropoesia\’, poetry concerned with the sensation and speed of flight. In 1933 he produced Futurist Words in Freedom/Tactile, Thermic, Olefactory,
        printed in coloured lithographs on metallic panels as pages of the Libro di latta aggressivo e contundente (1933), the world\’s first experimental
        object–book of poetry, produced by the Lito-latta Nosenzo of Savona.\n \n

        On 20 July 1942 he enrolled as a volunteer at the Russian Front, fighting in the battles of the Don, but was repatriated through illness after four
        months. In September 1944 in Venice, convalescing after an operation brought about by war fatigue, he gave to the Futurist painter and writer Giovanni
        Acquaviva (1900–72) his last Futurist manifesto La Patriarte (International Institute of Studies in Futurism, Milan, unpubd), in which he proposed an
        art of renewed expressive synthesis. In October 1944 he moved to Bellagio di Como where he was appointed keeper of the archives of the disbanded
        Accademia d\’Italia and died soon after.\n \n

        [1] Easton, E., W. (1981), \'Marinetti before the First Manifesto\', Art Journal, 4(41), 313-316. \n \n
        [2] Vinall S., W. (1980) \'Marinetti and the English Contributors to Poesia\', The Modern Language Review, 3(75), 547-560. \n \n
        [3] Ceroni, V. (1944) \'When Future Met It\'s Past (The Futurism of Fillipo T. Marinetti)\', The Modern Language Journal, 8(28), 665-673.

</string>

    <string name="umbertobio">

        Umberto Boccioni was born in Reggio di Calabria on the 19th October 1882. He was an influential painter and sculptor and helped shape the revolutionary aesthetic of The
        Futurist Movement. His approach to dynamism of form and the deconstruction of solid mass guided artists long after his death.\n \n

        [1] In all he had lived only thirty-four years. His devotion to literature and painting led him to Rome where, from 1892 until 1902. he worked in the
        studio of Giacomo Balla. a radical painter, then known as a divisionist.\n \n

        [2] Boccioni believed that scientific advances and the experience of modernity demanded that the artist abandon the tradition of depicting static,
        legible objects. The challenge, he believed, was to represent movement, the experience of flux, and the inter-penetration of objects. Boccioni
        summed up this project with the phrase, "physical transcendentalism."\n \n

        Boccioni\’s first major Futurist painting, Riot in the Gallery (1909), remained close to Pointillism and showed an affiliation with Futurism mainly in
        its violent subject matter and dynamic composition. The City Rises (1910–11), however, is an exemplary Futurist painting in its representation of
        dynamism, motion, and speed.\n \n

        Boccioni was probably influenced by Cubism in 1911–12, and about this time he also became interested in sculpture. In 1912 he published the “Manifesto
        of Futurist Sculpture,” several of whose suggestions anticipated developments in modern sculpture. Boccioni advocated the use in sculpture of
        non-traditional materials such as glass, wood, cement, cloth, and electric lights, and he called for the combination of a variety of materials in one
        piece of sculpture.\n \n

        Boccioni enlisted in the army during World War I and was killed by a fall from a horse in 1916. He was the most talented of the Futurist artists, and
        his untimely death marked the virtual end of the movement.\n \n

        [2] Although the Futurist movement is most associated with its founder, Filippo Tommaso Marinetti, its artistic direction owes much to Umberto Boccioni.
        He is responsible for producing the seminal texts on Futurist art, and was by and large the movement\'s most talented, technically proficient, and best
        educated artist. Despite the brevity of his career, he became a prolific student of avant-garde styles, while simultaneously striving to create
        something entirely novel: an art that uniquely expressed the speed, dynamism and tragedy of modern-day life.\n \n

        [1] Edwards, H. (1958), \'Umberto Boccioni\', The Art Institute of Chicago Quarterly, 2(52), 25-28.\n \n
        [2] The Art Story.org (?), Umberto Boccioni [online], available: http://bit.ly/XA7woS, [accessed 4th August 2014].

    </string>

    <string name="luigibio">

        Luigi Russolo was born on the 30th of April 1883. He was an Italian Futurist painter and composer, and the author of the manifesto The Art of
        Noises (1913). Russolo moved to Milan at the age of 16, although not enrolled at the Accademia di Bera he was often found in attendance and it was
        here in 1900 that the administration for the collection of modern painting started. This would act as an early influence for a young artist eager to
        find a contemporary style. \n \n

        [1] Russolo\’s imporant paintings include \'Music\', \'The Revolt\' and \'A Solidity of Fog\'. The revolt can be seen to encompass many of the futurist ideals.
        An all male crowd in rebellion at great speed in an urban environment. The painting could be categorized as Cubist, however it could also be seen to
        encompass the influences of Anton Giulio Bragaglia\'s photo-dynamism. Described in his article Futurist Photodynamism in Lacerba (Florence) July 1,
        1913 as \"an infinitesimal calculation of movement\". \n \n

        The Futurist Manifesto written by Billal Pratella in 1910 could be accredited to a change in direction for Russolo from painting to music. Russolo\’s
        epiphany came to him while he was attending the Constanzi Theatre in Rome listening to a futurist music performance. His concepts were a direct result
        of the performances of the Futurist musicians of that time.  He penned his thoughts, addressed to Balila Pratella, in a manifesto which was to be known
        as the Art of Noise.\n \n

        He felt his new concept required new instruments, a new orchestra and a new philosophy on music in general.[2] To this end both he and his accomplice
        Ugo Piatti worked day and night to create Intonarumori (Noise Makers) which would be befitting instruments for a new futurist orchestra and create the
        noises envisioned in the futurist manifesto.\n \n

        A performance of his Gran Concerto Futuristico (1917) was met with strong disapproval and violence from the audience, as Russolo himself had predicted.
        [2] None of his intoning devices have survived, though recently some have been reconstructed and used in performances. Although Russolo\'s works bear
        little resemblance to modern noise music, his pioneering creations cannot be overlooked as an essential stage in the evolution of the several genres
        in this category.\n \n

        Russolo died on the 4th of February 1947 in Cerro di Laveno, Lake Maggiore. leaving a legacy that would only come to fruition in the later part of the
        20th century and beyond.\n \n

        [1] Chilvers, I. (2012), \'Luigi Russolo\', The Oxford Dictionary of Art and Artists, Oxford University Press. \n \n
        [2] Brown, B. (1982), \'The Noise Instruments of Luigi Russolo\', Perspectives of New Music, 1/2(20), 31-48.

    </string>

    <string name="antoniobio">

        [1] Antonio Sant\'Elia was born on the 30th of April 1888 in Como, Italy. He was an Italian architect notable for his visionary drawings of the city of
        the future. In 1912 he began practicing architecture in Milan, where he became involved with the Futurist movement.\n \n

        [1] Between 1912 and 1914 he made many highly imaginative drawings and plans for cities of the future. A group of these drawings called Città Nuova
        (“New City”) was displayed in May 1914 at an exhibition of the Nuove Tendenze group, of which he was a member. Although Sant \'Elia\'s ideas were
        Futuristic, it has been questioned whether he was actually a member of the group. Essentially he was a socialist who felt that a complete break
        with architectural styles of the past and historic solutions to urban design was needed.\n \n

        In 1914 Antonio signed the "Manifesto of Futurist Architecture", the year he met Marinetti. The Futurists had been railing against the anachronism
        of the museum cities for five years before they found an architect to realize their visions. All of Sant\'Elia\'s projects were purely visionary as
        no futurist building was ever built.\n \n

        Excerpt From Manifesto of Futurist Architecture: \n \n

        No architecture has existed since 1700. A moronic mixture of the most various stylistic elements used to mask the skeletons of modern houses is
        called modern architecture. The new beauty of cement and iron are profaned by the superimposition of motley decorative incrustations that cannot
        be justified either by constructive necessity or by our (modern) taste, and whose origins are in Egyptian, Indian or Byzantine antiquity and in
        that idiotic flowering of stupidity and impotence that took the name of neoclassicism.\n \n

        The hundreds of Sant\'Elia\'s drawings that have survived depict various aspects and vistas of a highly mechanized and industrialized city, with
        skyscrapers and multilevel traffic circulation. A collection of these drawings is on permanent exhibition at Villa Olmo, near Como.\n \n

        Sant\'Elia volunteered for army duty shortly after the outbreak of World War I, and he died in the battle of Monfalcone. \n \n

        [1] Encyclopedia Britannica (2014), Antonia Sant\'Elia [online], available: http://bit.ly/1sg67fQ [accessed: 20 August 2014].

    </string>
    <string name="ginobio">

        Gino Severini was born on the 7th of April 1882 in Cortona Italy. He was an Italian painter who synthesized the styles of Futurism and Cubism.
        Severini began his painting career in 1900 as a student of Giacomo Balla, an Italian pointillist painter who later became a prominent Futurist.\n \n

        Stimulated by Balla\'s account of the new painting in France, Severini moved to Paris in 1906 and met leading members of the French avant-garde,
        such as the Cubist painters Georges Braque and Pablo Picasso and the writer Guillaume Apollinaire. Severini continued to work in the pointillist
        manner—an approach that entailed applying dots of contrasting colours according to principles of optical science—until 1910, when his signature was
        added to the Futurist painters’ manifesto.\n \n

        [1] Letters between Servini and Marinetti support the fact that Servini was actually in Paris at the time of the Manifesto but unequivocally
        supported it\'s content and seemed particularly pleased that Balla was a co-signatory. \n \n

        The Futurists wanted to revitalize Italian art (and, as a consequence, all of Italian culture) by depicting the speed and dynamism of modern life.
        Severini shared this artistic interest, but his work did not contain the political overtones typical of Futurism. Whereas Futurists typically painted
        moving cars or machines, Severini usually portrayed the human figure as the source of energetic motion in his paintings. \n \n

        Only briefly, in wartime works such as Red Cross Train Passing a Village (1914), did Severini paint subjects that conformed to the Futurist
        glorification of war and mechanized power. [1] These series of War paintings culminated in the well known The Armoured Train in Action from 1915. \n \n

        Severini published a book, Du cubisme au classicisme (1921; “From Cubism to Classicism”), in which
        he discussed his theories about the rules of composition and proportion. Later in his career he created many decorative panels, frescoes, and mosaics,
        and he became involved in set and costume design for the theatre. The artist\'s autobiography, Tutta la vita di un pittore (“The Life of a Painter”),
        was published in 1946.\n \n

        [1] Martin, M., W. (1980), \'Carissimo Marinetti\: Letters from Servini to the Futurist Chief\', Art Journal, 4(41), 305-312.

    </string>

    <string name="giocomobio">

    Giacomo Balla was born on the 18th of July in 1871. He was an art teacher and participated later in Futurism. In his art he created a pictorial depiction
    of light, movement and speed. Born in Turin, in the Piedmont region of Italy, Balla was the son of a photographer and as a child he studied music.\n \n

    At the age of 9 when his father died, he gave up music and began working in a lithograph print shop. Until age of twenty, his interest in art was such that he decided to
    study painting at local academies and exhibited several of his early works. Following academic studies at the University of Turin, Balla moved to Rome in 1895,
    where he met and married Elisa Marcucci. For several years he worked in Rome as an illustrator, a caricaturist, and also did portraiture. In 1899, his work was
    shown at the Venice Biennale. \n \n

    Around 1902, he taught Divisionist techniques to Umberto Boccioni and Gino Severini. Influenced by Filippo Tommaso Marinetti, Giacomo Balla adopted the
    Futurism style, creating a pictorial depiction of light, movement and speed. He was signatory to the Futurist Manifesto in 1910, and began designing and
    painting Futurist furniture, and also created Futurist \"antineutral\" clothing.\n \n

    In painting, his new style is demonstrated in Dynamism of a Dog on a Leash (1912 and his 1914 work titled Abstract Speed and Sound (Velocità astratta +
    rumore). In 1914, Balla also began sculpting, and the year after, created the well known sculpture, Boccioni\'s Fist.\n \n

    Balla along with leading Futurists Marinetti and Bruno Carra believed Cinema had a strong role to play in the evolution of Futurism. [1] This
    fascination with motion can be traced back to his 1904 painting The Workers Day. It in he explores the problem of motion and its relationship to
    painting. Balla believed that the cinema experience could transcend an experience given by a painting because \"Cinematography skills kills
    static contemplation\". He also stated \"While watching a Cinematographic performance we find ourselves watching a painting in motion which successively
    transforms itself to reproduce a given action\".\n \n

    During World War I, Balla\'s studio became the meeting place for young artists. By the end of the war, the Futurist movement showed signs of decline. In
    1935, he was made a member of Rome\'s Accademia di San Luca. In 1955, Balla participated in the documenta 1 in Kassel, Germany. He died March 1 1958.\n \n

    [1] Aiken, E. (1981), \'The Cinema and Italian Futurist Writing\', Art Journal, 4(41), 353-357. \n \n

    </string>

    <string name="brunobio">

    Bruno Munari was born on the 24th of October , 1907, in Milan. He was an Italian artist, designer, and inventor who contributed fundamentals to many fields
    of visual arts (painting, sculpture, film, industrial design, graphic design) in modernism, futurism, and concrete art, and in non visual arts (literature,
    poetry) with his research on games, didactic method, movement, tactile learning, kinesthetic learning, and creativity.\n \n

    Bruno Munari joined the \'Second\' Italian Futurist movement in Italy led by Filippo Tommaso Marinetti in the late 1920s. During this period, Munari
    contributed collages to Italian magazines, some of them highly propagandist, and created sculptural works which would unfold in the coming decades
    including his useless machines, and his abstract-geometrical works. After World War II Munari disassociated himself with Italian Futurism because of
    its proto-Fascist connotations. \n \n

    In 1948, Munari, Gillo Dorfles, Gianni Monnet and Atanasio Soldati, founded Movimento Arte Concreta (MAC), the Italian movement for concrete art. During
    the 1940s and 1950s, Munari produced many objects for the Italian design industry, including light fixtures, ash trays, televisions, espresso machines,
    and toys among other objects.\n \n

    In his late life, Munari worried by the incorrect perception of his artistic work, which is still confused with the other genres of his activity (didactics,
    design, graphics), selected art historian Miroslava Hajek as curator of a selection of his most important works in 1969. This collection, structured
    chronologically, shows his continuous creativity, thematical coherence and the evolution of his esthetical philosophy throughout all of his artistic life.\n \n

    Munari was also a huge contributor to the field of children\'s books and toys in his late life, though he had been producing books for children since the
    1930s. He used textured, tactile surfaces and cut-outs to create books that teach about touch, movement, and color through kinesthetic learning. \n \n

    [1] Pierpaolo, A., (2009), \'Beyond Futurism: Bruno Munari\'s Useless Machines\', Avant Garde Critical Studies, 315-336.

    </string>

    <string name="benedettabio">

    Benedetta Cappa was born on the 14th of August 1897 in Rome [1]. She became a member of the group in 1917 while she was painting under the tutelage of Giacomo Balla in Rome.
    In 1923 she married the group\'s founder, Filippo Tomasso Marinetti. The following year she attended the first Futurist Congress in Milan and participated
    in exhibitions from 1927 through to the end of World War II. These exhibitions included appearances at the Venice Biennale (1926, 1930, 1934, 1936)
    the Rome Quadrienniale. \n \n

    As a writer of experimental novels and as an artist, her subjects are quintessentially Futurist. In works such as Irradiazone di un
    nucleo in sviluppo (Irradiation of a Nucleus in Development) and Luce + rumori di treno notturno (Light + Sounds of a Nocturnal Train),fluid lines and
    repeated abstract motifs convey velocity and motion. In the latter painting, triangular elements of metal, collaged to the surface, create a raised tactile
    surface known as tattilismo. During the 1920s, Filippo and Benedetta developed this genre of mixed-media works intended to visually stimulate the sensory
    experience of running one\'s fingers over a variety of surfaces.\n \n

    Benedetta was also a major proponent of aeropittura (aeropainting), which often took the form of fantastic and imagined aerial views. In Incontro sull\'isola
    (Meeting on the Island),she offers an unfettered vista of sea and shore, as if the viewer were hovering in midair. Her monumental 1934 work for the Palermo
    post office, is a large-scale mural of five painted panels: Synthesis of Sea, Radio, Air, Rail, and Telephone and Telegraph Communications.\n \n

    After her husband died [2] Benedetta stopped creating Artwork and instead focused on the preservation of the Futurist movement. This could not have been
    an easy task considering the Futurist connections with the Facist Regime. She died in Venice in 1977 leaving a legacy that is still not fully understood.\n \n

    [1] Gale, T. (2007), Marinetti, Benedetta Cappa (1987-1977) [online], available: http://bit.ly/1oZ8ZtV [accessed: 20 August 2014].\n \n
    [2] Conaty, S., M. (2009), \'Benedetta Cappa Marinetti and the Second Wave of Futurism\', Woman\'s Art Journal, 1(30), 19-28.


    </string>

    <string name="carlobio">

    [1] Carlo Carra was born on the 11th of February 1881, in Quargnento near Alessandria. He  was an Italian painter, a leading figure of the Futurist movement
    that flourished in Italy during the beginning of the 20th century. In addition to his many paintings, he wrote a number of books concerning art. He taught
    for many years in the city of Milan.\n \n

    In 1899-1900, Carra was in Paris decorating pavilions at the Exposition Universelle, where he became acquainted with contemporary French art. He then
    spent a few months in London in contact with exiled Italian anarchists, and returned to Milan in 1901.\n \n

    In 1906, he enrolled at Brera Academy (Accademia di Brera) in the city, and studied under Cesare Tallone. In 1910 he signed, along with Umberto
    Boccioni, Luigi Russolo and Filippo Tommaso Marinetti the Manifesto of Futurist Painters, and began a phase of painting that became his most popular
    and influential.\n \n

    [1] Carra\'s Futurist phase ended around the time World War I began. His work, while still using some Futurist concepts, began to deal more clearly with form
    and stillness, rather than motion and feeling. Carra soon began creating still lifes in a style he, along with Giorgio de Chirico, called
    "metaphysical painting". Throughout the 1920s and 1930s, the metaphysical phase gave way to a sombre style akin to Masaccio\'s. An example from this
    period is his 1928 painting Morning by the Sea.\n \n

    He is best known for his 1911 futurist work, The Funeral of the Anarchist Galli. Carra was indeed an anarchist as a young man but, along with many other
    Futurists, later held more reactionary political views, becoming ultra-nationalist and irredentist before and during the war, as well as by Fascism after
    1918 (in the 1930s, Carra signed a manifesto in which called for support of the state ideology through art). The Strapaese group he joined, founded by
    Giorgio Morandi, was strongly influenced by fascism and responded to the neo-classical guidelines which had been set by the regime after 1937 (but was
    opposed to the ideological drive towards strong centralism). He died in Milan in 1966. \n \n

    [1] Pasqualeart (2014), Carlo Carra [online], available: http://bit.ly/1p3bWjd [accessed: 20 August 2014].\n \n

    </string>

    <string name="francescobio">

    Francesco Balilla Pratella was born on the February 1880 in Lugo Italy. He was an Italian composer, musicologist and essayist. One of the leading advocates
    of futurism in Italian music, much of Pratella\'s own music betrays little obvious connection to the views espoused in the manifesti he authored.\n \n

    An early project drawn from Pratella\'s interest in indigenous folksong was the opera La Sina d\'Varguõn (1909), which attracted the attention of Filippo
    Tommaso Marinetti, the father of Italian futurism. \n \n

    Pratella joined the futurist group in 1910 [1] after meeting with Marinetti at a recital of Pratella\'s music in Imola. At this time he became one of the
    movements most ardent activists, publishing three tracts which were combined into the pamphlet Musica Futurista in 1912. Pratella\'s first and second
    concerts as a Futurist musician proved to be provocative affairs. He performed his composition Musica Futurista with a great orchestra, with all the
    leading futurists in attendance. The second performance March the 9th proved to be a riotous affair sending the crowd into a rage as had been
    predicted before the performance began. \n \n

    Inspired by Pratella, Luigi Russolo created his Intonorumori (Noise Intoners) in 1913 and wrote his own manifesto, The Art of Noise (1913), introducing
    the futurist concept of noise in music. Pratella was less than enthusiastic about the Intonorumori, but he agreed to utlize their resources
    in his opera L\'aviatore Dro (1911-1914) which was written in close collaboration with Marinetti.\n \n

    At the end of World War I, Pratella broke with the futurists; L\'aviatore Dro opened in 1920 and proved popular with critics and audiences alike, but its
    impracticality and odd storyline doomed it to certain obscurity.\n \n

    According to Pratella, Italian music was inferior to music abroad. He praised the "sublime genius" of Wagner and saw some value in the work of Richard
    Strauss, Debussy, Elgar, Mussorgsky, Glazunov and Sibelius. By contrast, the Italian symphony was dominated by opera in an "absurd and anti-musical form".
    The conservatories encouraged backwardness and mediocrity. \n \n

    [1] Payton, R., J. (1976), \'The Music of Futurism: Concerts and Polemics\', The Musical Quarterly, 1(62), 25-45.

    </string>
    <string name="futurbio">

    [1] Italian Futurism was officially launched in 1909 when Filippo Tommaso Marinetti, an Italian intellectual, published his “Founding and Manifesto of
    Futurism” in the French newspaper Le Figaro. Marinetti\’s continuous leadership ensured the movement’s cohesion for three and half decades, until his
    death in 1944.\n \n

    Futurismo Manifesti allowed the movement to progress rapidly into mainstream culture and the Italian political landscape. [2] The movement remarkably
    had little detractor\'s and was able to recruit a new generation of Futurists throughout the 1920\'s. This was helped by the circulation of Manifesti
    through publications such as Lacerba, La Voce, L\'Italia Futurista, and Stile Futurista.\n \n

    [1] To be a Futurist in the Italy of the early 20th century was to be modern, young, and insurgent. Inspired by the markers of modernity the industrial
    city, machines, speed, and flight. Futurism’s adherents exalted the new and the disruptive. They sought to revitalize what they determined to be a
    static, decaying culture and an impotent nation that looked to the past for its identity. Futurism began as a literary avant-garde, and the printed
    word was vital for this group. Manifestos, words-in-freedom poems, novels, and journals were intrinsic to the dissemination of their ideas. But the
    Futurists quickly embraced the visual and performing arts, politics, and even advertising.\n \n

    [1] Futurist artists experimented with the fragmentation of
    form, the collapsing of time and space, the depiction of dynamic motion, and dizzying perspectives. Their style evolved from fractured elements in
    the 1910s to a mechanical language in the ’20s, and then to aerial imagery in the ’30s. No vanguard exists in a void—all are touched by their
    historical context. The Futurists’ celebration of war as a means to remake Italy and their support of Italy’s entrance into World War I also constitute
    part of the movement’s narrative, as does the later, complicated relationship between Futurism and Italian fascism.\n \n

    [1] Guggenheim (2014), Italian Futurism Reconstructing the Universe [online], available: http://bit.ly/1c1MrJB, [accessed 18th August 2014].\n \n
    [2] Golan, R. (2010), \'Futurism Redux\', Modernism/modernity, 1(17), 223-231.

    </string>
    <string name="fortunatobio" >

    Fortunato Depero was born on the 30th of March 1892 in Fondo, Trentino. Depero grew up in Rovereto and it was here he first began exhibiting his works, while
    serving as an apprentice to a marble worker. It was on a 1913 trip to Florence that he discovered a copy of the paper Lacerba and an article by one of
    the founders of the futurism movement, Filippo Tommaso Marinetti.\n \n

    [1] Like many of his Futurist contemporaries Depero ignored traditional divisions between the arts. He practiced painting sculpture and graphic design.
    Depero was inspired, and in 1914 moved to Rome and met fellow futurist Giacomo Balla. It was with Balla in 1915 that he wrote the manifesto Ricostruzione
    futurista dell\’universo ("Futurist Reconstruction of the Universe") which expanded upon the ideas introduced by the other futurists. \n \n

    In 1919 Depero founded the "Casa d'Arte Futurista" (House of Futurist Art) in Rovereto, which specialised in producing toys, tapestries and furniture in
    the futurist style. In 1925 he represented the futurists at the Exposition Internationale des Arts Décoratifs et Industriels Modernes (International
    Exposition of Modern Industrial and Decorative Arts).\n \n

    [2] While Depero never painted as compellingly as Balla, sculpted as powerfully as Boccioni, or composed as originally as Russolo, the freedom with which he
    moved between media over the course of his five-decade career made him Futurism\’s common denominator. Indeed, his masterpiece wouldn\’t be in painting but in
    architecture, specifically a trade fair pavilion for the 1927 Monza Biennale Internazionale delle Arti Decorative that had an immaculate white facade and
    larger-than-life block letters for walls. \n \n

    In his 1931 manifesto dell\'arte pubblicitaria he proclaimed "the art of the future will be largely advertising". This was visionary thinking for the time
    and indeed came to fruition decades later in the advertising boom of the 50\'s and 60\'s. He returned to Roverto Italy after a stint working in the United
    States where he pursued his idea\'s on advertising and graphics.\n \n

    Fortunato achieved one of his many long term ambitions and opened the Galleria Museo Depero on in August 1959 which houses many Furutist works.
    He died on November 29th 1960 after being ill with diabetes.\n \n

    [1] Doordan D., P. (1989), \'The Advertising Architecture of Fortunato Depero\', The Journal of Decorative and Propaganda Arts, 1(12), 46-55.\n \n
    [2] Forbes, (2009), \'Fortunato Depero\'s Italian Futurism\' [online], available: http://onforb.es/1rmTwvv, [accessed 4th August 2014].

    </string>
    <string name="brunocbio" >

        Bruno Corra was born in Ravenna on the 9th of June 1892. He was a noted member of the first wave of the Italian Futurist movement. He first practiced
        as a painter and then abandoned painting to concentrate on abstract cinema. \n \n

        Bruno and his brother Arnaldo Ginna both under assumed pseudonym\'s created a book called Method and New Life in which they described a future in
        which non-figurative painting could be combined with chromatic music.\n \n

        During the period from 1910 to 1912 Bruno collaborated with his brother again this time shifting their focus to abstract short movies on which colour
        was directly applied to untreated film frames. The Cinepitture created consisted of overlapping colours and geometric shapes accompanied by futurist
        soundscapes. \n \n

        [1] Carra believed Cinema was an important part of the Futurist aesthetic. In his 1913 manifesto The Painting of Sounds, Noises and Smells Carra
        declared that Futurist paintings "express the plastic equivalent of the sounds, noises and smells found in theatres, music halls, and cinemas".\n \n

        In 1915 he collaborated with Marinetti and Emilio Settimelli on the Manifesto of The Futurist Synthetic Theatre. In it they condemned contemporary
        Italian Theatre of the time for being too explanatory, diluted and static. They argued for a new type of theatre that was brief and could condense
        innumerable situations, sensibilities, and ideas into short words and gestures. \n \n

        During the years after World War I he collaborated again with Marinetti and his brother Arnaldo to create the film Futurist Life although sadly
        only a tiny proportion of the composition still exist today. To coincide with this period he co-authored the manifest of Futurist Cinema in which they
        denounced the means in which film makers of the day communicated thought processes.\n \n

        After 1917 he moved away from to Futurist movement to pursue a highly successful career as a novelist. Corra died in Varese
        on the 20th of November 1976.\n \n

       [1] Aiken, E. (1981), \'The Cinema and Italian Futurist Writing\', Art Journal, 4(41), 353-357.\n \n

    </string>
    <string name="icons" />
    <string name="app_not_available" />
    <string name="action_websearch" />
    <string name="search_hint" />
    <string name="action_map" />
    <string name="share_menu" />

</resources>

